travelaudience.com 2019-12-30

# travel audience - website privacy policy

## travel audience – Website Privacy Policy

LAST UPDATED – October 2018

We, travel audience GmbH, are concerned about privacy issues and want you to be familiar with how we collect, use and disclose Personal Information (i.e. information that identifies you as an individual) on our website.

## What is the Purpose of this Privacy Policy?

We want to ensure that you become familiar with our processes for the entry, use and disclosure of personal data (data, which you identify as an individual). This Privacy Policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) that is applicable for this website of the travel audience GmbH describes the processes applied by us in connection with the information entered by you via this website and with the information that we may collect through our website accessible under the URL www.travelaudience.com (the “Site”). It does not refer to the entry, use or disclosure of data, which were entered or recorded in any other manner than via the website.

We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy. The detail “last update” at the beginning of this page informs you of the time at which this Privacy Policy was last revised. All changes to our Privacy Policy will become effective as soon as we publish the revised Privacy Policy on the website. The use of the website following such changes implies your consent to the now applicable revised Privacy Policy.

We would first of all now like to ensure that you are aware of the bodies which you can contact in connection with any questions:

## Name and Address of the Controller

The Controller within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation and other national data protection laws of the member states as well as other provisions under data protection law is:

travel audience GmbH  
Elsenstraße 106  
12435 Berlin  
Germany  
T: +49 30 530 230 610  
E-Mail: privacy@travelaudience.com

Should you have any questions relating to this Privacy Policy please contact us by e-mail under the following address [privacy@travelaudience.com](mailto:privacy@travelaudience.com)

## Contact data of the data protection officer

The data protection officer of travel audience GmbH can be reached by normal mail under Data protection officer, travel audience GmbH, Elsenstraße 106, 12435 Berlin, Germany or by e-mail [privacy@travelaudience.com](mailto:privacy@travelaudience.com)

## An initial overview

It is very important to us that you are informed in full which personal data we may collect in relation to you and how we use these. The type and the scope of the personal data, which we collect and process are decisively determined according to how you use our website. It is also decisive which information you enter when using the website. We and other service providers enter and process the information stated by you at different times when using the website to a varied extent, depending on the type of use of this website.

travel audience principally only collects and uses your personal data insofar as this is necessary in order to provide a functional website as well as our contents and services.

## What are personal data and which types are recorded on this website?

**Personal data** is any information, which refers to an identified or identifiable natural person. This is therefore all data, which identify you as an individual or make identifiable. For example name, postal address, telephone number, e-mail address.

The processing of personal data is only carried out if this is permitted by statutory regulations.

We will present to you in detail below, which personal data we collect, how and why we process these and on which legal basis this takes place.

## How we use the personal data entered by you

We use the entered personal data for the following purposes:

  * In order to process your inquiries (e.g. in order to have news and updates sent to you and in order to answer your questions).
  * In order to obtain remarks and comments (e.g. within the scope of a survey).
  * In order to send you important information with regard to the website, changes to our business terms and conditions and guidelines and/or other administration-related information.
  * If you consent or if permitted by virtue of the law in order to inform you by e-mail about products and services, special and promotion offers and to send you other marketing material that could possibly be of interest to you.
  * If you have consented in order to evaluate your usage behavior with regard to the newsletters sent by us, operated websites and the used links or executed downloads for a better and more personal service.
  * In order to enable you to participate in prize draws, competitions and similar advertising actions (collectively referred to as “advertising actions”). You should read the rules, if available, of each advertising action, in which you take part, carefully as under certain circumstances they contain important additional information about the use of your personal data. Insofar as the provisions of such rules with regard to the handling of personal data stand in contradiction to this Privacy Policy, the provisions of the respective rules shall be deemed as decisive.
  * For internal business purposes, e.g. data analysis, audits, development of new products, extension of our website, improvement of our services, identification of trends for use and assessment of the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns.

## The legal framework for the use of your personal data

The use of the entered personal data is only carried out as envisaged in the EU General Data Protection Regulation ( **GDPR** ):

  * If necessary for the processing of personal data, we will obtain your consent pursuant to **6 Para.  1 lit. a**.
  * If the processing of your personal data serves to fulfil a contract, in which you participate as a contractual party, **6 Para.  1 lit. b** GDPR is the legal basis. This shall also apply to processing activities, which are necessary for the execution of pre-contractual measures.
  * If we process your personal data in order to fulfil a legal obligation, this is based on **6 Para.  1 lit. c** GDPR.
  * If vital interests of the data subject or another natural person renders a processing of personal data necessary this shall take place owing to **6 Para.  1 lit. d** GDPR.
  * If the processing is necessary in order to safeguard a legitimate interest of our company or a third party and if the interests, fundamental rights and fundamental freedom of the data subject do not outweigh the first mentioned interest then 6 Para. 1 lit. f GDPR will serve as a legal basis for the processing.

If you follow this link

[http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&rid=1](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&rid=1)

you can read the entire text of the GDPR law.

After this general overview of the use of your personal data and their legal bases, we will present to you below for the individual case how and why we process your personal data, how long we store these for and which rights you have.

## What happens when you merely pay a visit to our website in order to inform yourself about us?

With the mere informational use of our website, therefore if you do not register or otherwise send information, we will only collect the personal data, which your b. If you would like to view our website, we will collect the following data, which are necessary for us from a technical point of view in order to display our website to you and the guarantee the stability and security, the legal basis is Art 6 Para. 1 S. 1 lit. f GDPR:

**Technical data:  
**These include  
Your registration data,  
Type and version of your browser,  
Your time zone setting,  
Type and version of your browser plugins,  
Your operating system and your platform.

**Location data:  
**If you use the website we enter details relating to your geographical data. These location details enable us to offer you location-based products and services at the respective time. They will, however, not be stored by us or forwarded to third parties.

**Non-personal data:  
**Collected information relating to your use of the website, your full URL-click stream (Uniform Resource Locator), via the and from the website (with details of data and time), the products displayed or searched for by you, answer times of the sites, download errors, duration of the display of certain sites, Information relating to the site interactions (how e.g. scrolling, clicking and mouse-over) as well as the methods used to leave the site.

## What happens with your personal data when you have left our website again?

If you have sufficiently informed yourself about us on our website and left it again without, for example, having registered for our newsletter or without carrying out any further action, we will store your data, which are necessary for the operation of our homepage after 14 months.

The aforementioned shall apply to the visit to our website purely for informational purposes. Our website, however, offers many different possibilities for usage and contact. Depending on which offers you use, your personal data will be stored and processed to a varying extent. Below we have presented for you in detail what the respective type of usage means for the handling of your personal data.

## Why we use cookies on our website?

travel audience and other service providers record details in relation to your person by using cookies.

With the first access to our website an easily perceivable so-called “cookie banner” will appear. With the first access you have the possibility to approve or refuse the use of cookies in the “cookie banner”. Please note that the “cookie banner” will no longer be displayed – not with a repeated visit to the website either -, as soon as you have approved the use of cookies. You can of course deactivate cookies again at all times as requested. This button allows the  deactivation function for the cookies.

## What is a cookie?

A cookie is a text file with small quantities of information, which is downloaded onto your device (computer, mobile device) when a website is visited. A cookie is sent back to the original website with each visit to the website or a website, which recognizes this cookie. Cookies are helpful as websites can recognize the device of a user with the help of cookies.

## Which types of cookies are there?

There are two main types of cookies: Session Cookies and Persistent Cookies.

**Session Cookies** are only allocated to your computer or mobile device for the duration of the visit to a website and will be deleted as soon as you close the browser.

**Persistent Cookies** , on the other hand, are stored on your device until they are deleted or expire.

## Which cookies are used on this website?

**Absolutely necessary cookies _  
_** These are necessary in order for you to be able to navigate on the website and can use its functions, e.g. with the access to secure areas of the website. Without these cookies services requested by you cannot be made available. These cookies do not collect any information about you, which can be used for marketing purposes. We have a legitimate interest in the use of these cookies as otherwise you cannot use our website, or we cannot present our website to you in a functional manner.

**Function-related cookies _  
_** These collect information concerning how this website is used by you. For example, information can be collected regarding which pages you have visited more frequently or when you have received an error message from one of the pages on this website. These cookies do not collect direct information, which identifies you.

**Functionality cookies _  
_** With the help of these cookies the website can remember your individual settings, the preferred language or the region, in which you are located. The website subsequently uses this information to provide improved functions. These cookies can also be used in order to remember changes, which you have made to text size, font and other adjustable parts of the website. Even if the information collected by these cookies is anonymous, these cookies can identify you in combination with other data, because they track certain information of your internet provider for your settings.

**Target-oriented cookies _  
_** These cookies collect various items of information about your surfing habits. These cookies store that you have visited various websites, and transmits the information to other companies, e.g. advertising companies. The pursued purpose is to display target-oriented advertising to you, which are more relevant for you and your interests. Although these cookies can track your visits to websites in the internet, the cookies themselves do not usually know where you are located. Without these cookies the online advertisements displayed to you are of less relevance for you and your interests.

## How can cookies be restricted or blocked?

You can adjust the settings of your browser so that cookies, which are set by the website (or another website in the internet), are restricted or blocked. In your browser you will find information about the adjustment to your settings. On [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) you will find general information about cookies as well as the adjustment of cookie settings for the various browsers.

Under the following link we have compiled an overview for you of the cookies most frequently used by us on this website: [Cookie List](https://travelaudience.com/cookie-list/)

### What happens when you register for our newsletter?

On our website you have the possibility to register for our free newsletter. If you sign up for the newsletter we will regularly provide you with news worth knowing about our compan.

If you want to receive our newsletter you have to register for the dispatch on our website or in writing and have a valid e-mail address. In order to receive our newsletter you have to register on our website or in writing and have a valid email address.

With the registration for our newsletter we process the personal data requested from you in the input mask: Firstname, Lastname, email address

The legal basis for the data processing owing to your consent is Art. 6 Para. 1 lit .a GDPR.

We exclusively use your personal data, which you have provided to us with the registration for the newsletter, for sending the newsletter. We do not forward these data to third parties, if there is no statutory obligation for the forwarding or this serves the purpose of criminal prosecution.

You can unsubscribe from our newsletter at all times. In the newsletter you will find a corresponding link for this purpose. If you have unsubscribed from the newsletter we will delete the entered personal data.

### Why we use newsletter tracking

Our newsletters include so-called tracking pixel. A tracking pixel is a miniature graphic. It is embedded into e-mails, which are sent in the HTML format. This serves to enable a log file recording and a log file analysis. This way a statistical evaluation of the success or failure of online marketing campaigns is carried out. Based on the embedded tracking pixel we can recognize whether and when you have opened an e-mail and which links located in the e-mail you have called.

We store and evaluate the personal data collected through the tracking pixel contained in the newsletter. This way we can optimize the newsletter dispatch and adjust the contents of future newsletters even better to your interests.

We do not forward the processed personal data to third parties. At all times you are entitled to revoke the separate declaration of consent granted in this respect via the Double-Opt-In procedure. After a revocation your personal data will be deleted by us. An unsubscription from the receipt of the newsletter will automatically be understood as a revocation.

## What happens with your personal data if you use the contact form on our website or contact us by e-mail

On our website we offer you the possibility to contact us via a contact form. Your personal data, which you enter in the contact form, will be transmitted to us and we store these.

The following personal data are collected for the contact form:

–          Firstname

–          Lastname

–          E-mail address

As soon as you have sent the contact form to us we will process from you:

–          Date and time of the registration

–          Your potential interest in receiving our newsletter (via check box)

The processing of your personal data is only carried out if you have granted us your consent here to when completing the contact form.

If you contact us via e-mail we will store and process the personal data transmitted to us with your e-mail.

Your personal data will not be forwarded to third parties if there is no statutory obligation for the forwarding or this serves the purpose of criminal prosecution. With the existence of your consent the processing of your personal data is based on Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. a GDPR. If contact is made per e-mail we will process your personal data based on Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f GDPR. If the e-mail serves the conclusion of a contract then Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b GDPR is the legal basis for the data processing.

The personal data provided by you in the contact form or your e-mail will solely be used to process the communication with you. We use the personal data, which are processed during the sending process, in order to prevent misuse of the contact form and to secure our IT systems.

If your personal data is no longer required for the above mentioned purpose, we will erase it. If you contacted us via email or the contact form the erasure will take place as soon as concern that ensues from the contact is ended, i.e. has been finally clarified.

We will delete the data, which are processed for the sending process, within three years.

If you have used the contact form or have contacted us by e-mail you can revoke your consent to the processing of your personal data at all times by sending an email [privacy@travelaudience.com](mailto:info@travelaudience.com)

In cases of an objection or revocation we must end the further communication with you. We will delete all of your personal data.

### Web-Analytic Tools

We use so-called Web-Analytic Tools on our website. Below we will explain to you in detail which tools we use, why we do this and which implications this has on your personal data.

## The use of Google Analytics on our website

**How Google Analytics works and why we use it**

On our website we use Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. (“Google”).

Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which enable an analysis on how you  use  the website. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this website is as a rule transmitted to a server of Google in the USA and is stored there. In the event of the activation of the IP anonymization on this website, your IP address is however abbreviated previously by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Treaty on the European Economic Area. Your full IP address will not be transmitted to a server of Google in the USA. By order of the operator of this website Google will use this information in order to evaluate your use of the website in order to compile reports on the website-activities and in order to provider further services associated with the website use and the internet use towards the website operator.

The IP address transmitted by your browser within the scope of Google Analytics is not aggregated with other data of Google.

We use Google Analytics in order to analyze the use of our website and in order to be able to improve it regularly. Through the gained statistics we can improve our range of offers and design it moreinteresting for you. For the exceptional cases, in which personal data is transferred to the USA, Google has submitted itself to the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.

On our website we use Google Analytics moreover for a cross-device analysis of visitor flows, which is carried out via a user-ID. In your customer account, go to “My data”, “personal data”, you can deactivate the cross-device analysis of your use.

**How can the use of Google Analytics be prevented and which consequences will this have?**

You can prevent the storage of the cookies by adjusting the setting of your browser software; however we would like to point out that in this case you may not be able to use all functions of this website in full. In addition you can prevent the entry of the data generated by the cookie and which refer to your use of the website (incl. your IP address) to Google as well as the processing of these data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available under the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>.

This website uses Google Analytics with the extension “_anonymizeIp()”. This way IP addresses will be abbreviated for further use, this way there’s no possibility to make a reference to a person. Insofar as the data collected in relation to you have a reference to persons, this will thus be excluded immediately and the personal data therefore deleted immediately.

The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is Art. 6 Para. 1 S. 1 lit. f GDPR.

**You can find further information here**

Information of the third party provider: Google Dublin, Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, Fax: +353 (1) 436 1001. Conditions of use: <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html>,

Overview regarding data protection: <http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/learn/privacy.html>,

as well as the privacy statement: <http://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy>.

## LinkedIn Tracking

The LinkedInTracking Pixels consist of a JavaScript code that we have added to our website to enable in-depth campaign reporting and to help us unlock valuable insights about our website visitors. This JavaScript code will only be activated after you agree to accept cookies from our website.  We use the LinkedIn Tracking to track conversions, retarget website visitors, and unlock additional insights about members interacting with our LinkedIn adverts. The LinkedIn Insight Tag enables the collection of metadata such as IP address information, timestamp, and events such as page views. All data is encrypted. The LinkedIn browser cookie is stored in a visitor’s browser until they delete the cookie or the cookie expires. You can opt out of cookies from LinkedIn on your [LinkedIn settings page](https://www.linkedin.com/settings/?trk=) and recommend you read their [Cookie Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy) for more information.

## Zendesk

We also use the helpdesk system Zendesk to faciliate communication with the visitors of our website; directly via live chat.

The according functions are supplied by Zendesk, Inc., 989 Market Street #300, San Francisco, CA 94102, USA, who have concluded an order data processing agreement.

We are not storing any data or chat history.

You can find more information in the [Zendesk privacy policy](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/).

### The use of Social-Media Plugins

We currently use the following Social-Media-Plugins :

  * Facebook
  * Twitter
  * LinkedIn

We use the so-called 2-click-solution. So when you visit our site for the first time principally no personal data are forwarded to the providers of these plugins. You can identify the provider of the plugin through the marking on the grayed box based on the first letter. Only if you click on one of the plugins personal data will be transmitted: By the activation of the plugin data are transmitted automatically to the respective plugin provider and stored there (at US providers in the USA). We neither have an influence on the collected data and data processing activities, nor are we aware of the full scope of the data collection, the purposes as well as the storage deadlines.

When you activate a plugin the plugin provider receives the information that you have called the corresponding sub-page of our online offer. Moreover, the data stated below will be transmitted, whereby in the event of Facebook according to the details of the respective provider in Germany only an anonymized IP is collected. This is carried out irrespective whether you have an account at this plugin provider and are logged in there. If you are logged into the plugin-provider, these data will be allocated directly to your account. If you press the activated button and e.g. link the site, the plugin provider will also store this information in your user account and will publicly share this with your contacts. If you do not wish to have the allocation with your profile at the plugin provider you must log out before activating the button.

The plugin provider will store these data as usage profiles and uses these for purposes of advertising, market research and /or design of its website suitable for the needs. Such an evaluation is in particular carried out (also for users who are not logged in) for the presentation of advertising suitable for the needs and in order to inform other users of the social network about your activities on our website. You are entitled to a right of objection against the formation of these user profiles, whereby you must contact the respective plugin provider in order to exercise this right.

You can obtain further information for the purpose and scope of the data collection and their processing by the plugin provider in the privacy statements of these providers notified below. There you can also receive further information pertaining to your rights in this respect and possibilities for settings for the protection of your privacy.

Addresses of the respective providers and URL with their privacy notices:

Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, USA;

http://www.facebook.com/policy.php; further information pertaining to data collection:

http://www.facebook.com/help/186325668085084

http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info-on-other applications and http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/your-info everyoneinfo.

Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, California 94103, USA; <https://twitter.com/privacy>.

LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, California 94043, USA; <http://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>.

### Integration of the services of third parties

We have integrated YouTube videos into our online offer, which are stored on [http://www.YouTube.com](http://www.youtube.com/) and can be played back directly from our website. These are all integrated in the “extended data protection mode”, i.e. that no data about you as user are transmitted to YouTube if you do not play the videos back. Only when you playback the videos will the data previously stated under plugins be transmitted. We have no influence on this data transmission.

### Forwarding of personal data to third parties

At the beginning of this privacy statement we explained to you for which purposes we process your personal data. We are an internationally organized company and part of the Amadeus Group this entails that we have to forward your personal data to third parties in order to provide optimum services for you. This shall also include a cross-border exchange of personal data. This is decisive for the provision of our services.

Third parties, to which we transmit data are:

  * Business partners, suppliers, subcontractors and service providers for the execution of a contract, which we have concluded with these companies or with you.
  * In order to prove your identity towards all persons, to whom you send messages with information relating to the website directly via the website.
  * To sponsors of advertising actions (irrespective whether the advertising actions are organized by us) or otherwise in compliance with the rules applicable for the respective advertising action. You should read the rules, if available, of each advertising action, in which you take part, carefully as under certain circumstances they contain important additional information about the use of your personal data by sponsors or third parties. Insofar as the provisions of such rules with regard to the handling of personal data stand in contradiction to this Privacy Policy, the provisions of the respective rules shall be deemed as decisive.
  * To analysts and providers of search engines, which support us with the improvement and optimization of our website.
  * To group companies respectively to third parties in the event of a restructuring, a merger, a sale, a Joint Venture, an assignment, a transfer or all other disposals over the business operation, the fixed assets or the warehouse stocks/shareholdings in their entirety or in parts (including without a restriction in conjunction with insolvency or comparable proceedings).

It is of upmost importance to us particularly that your personal data are stored and transmitted in a secure manner. For this reason we only transmit data outside of the European Economic Area or the EEA (i.e. the member states of the European Union as well as Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein) if this complies with the data protection law and the channel for the transmission offers appropriate protection for your personal data.

This is the case:

  * if a data transmission agreement is available, which includes the current standard contractual clauses, which the European Commission envisages for the transmission of personal data by responsible parties in the EEA to responsible parties and contract processors in legal systems without appropriate data protection law, or
  * by the signing of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework for the transmission of personal data from companies in the EU to companies in the USA or an equivalent agreement between other legal system, or
  * the transmission of your data to a country, in which a standard of data protection exists as stipulated by law that was assessed as appropriate by the European Commission, or
  * if it is necessary for the conclusion or the processing of a contract between us and a third party and the transmission is in your interest for the purpose of this contract (for example if we must transmit data outside of the EEA in order to fulfill our obligations from this contract if you are a customer of our company), or
  * if you have granted your consent for the data transmission.

In order to ensure that your personal data enjoy an appropriate degree of protection we have implemented suitable measures with third parties with which we share your personal data in order to ensure that your personal data are processed by these third parties in a manner that is consistent with the data protection rights that is in line with the data protection laws.

You can read the legal provisions of the GDPR concerning the forwarding of data to third parties in the full text here _http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679 &rid=1._

### Security

In order to guarantee the protection of the personal data controlled by us, we take all organizational, technical and administration-related measures to a reasonable extent. Unfortunately, no 100% security can be guaranteed for data transmissions via the internet or for data storage systems. Please do not send us any confidential information by e-mail. If you have cause to assume that your interaction with us is no longer secure (if, for example, you are convinced that the safety of an account, which you have set up in our company, is no longer guaranteed), you must inform us of the problem without delay by contacting us using the contact information on the website (please note that if you contact us by normal post the processing of your problem by us may be delayed). Moreover, please note that the communication by e-mail it not inevitably secure. Accordingly, you should not enter any credit card information in your e-mail correspondence with us.

### Duration of the storage / deletion

We have explained to you above for the respective individual case how long we store your personal data and when we delete them.

In general we will store your personal data during a deadline, which is required in order to fulfill the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer storage deadline is necessary or is permitted by virtue of the law.

If the purpose of the storage ceases to apply or if a storage deadline expires that is (has been) stipulated by the European body for the issue of Directive and Regulations or another responsible legislator, the personal data will be blocked or deleted as a routine and in compliance with the statutory regulations.

### Instruction regarding the use of the website by children

The website is not oriented to individuals under the age of eighteen (18) years old. We request these persons not to make any personal data available via the website.

### Rights of the data subjects

According to the GDPR you are entitled to the following rights against us:

**Right of access by the data subject pursuant to Art.  15 GDPR**

**Right to rectification Art.  16 GDPR**

**Right to erasure (“right to be forgotten”) Art.  17 GDPR**

**Right to restriction of processing Art.  18 GDPR**

**Right to notification Art.  19 GDPR**

**Right to data portability Art.  20 GDPR**

The following link [http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&rid=1](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&rid=1) leads you directly to the text of the GDPR law

### Separate information relating to the right of the data subject to file an objection Art. 21 GDPR

You have the right, for reasons, which arise from your special situation, to file an objection at all times against the processing of the personal data relating to you that is carried out owing to Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. e or f GDPR; this shall also apply to a profiling that is supported on these provisions.

We will no longer process the personal data relating to you, unless we can proof essential reasons worthy of protection for the processing, which outweigh your interests, rights and freedom, or the processing serves the assertion, exercising or defense against legal claims.

If the personal data relating to you are processed in order to conduct direct advertising you have the right to file an objection against the processing of the personal data relating to you for the purpose of such advertising at all times; this shall also apply to the profiling insofar as it is associated with such direct advertising.

If you object to the processing for purposes of direct advertising then the personal data relating to you will no longer be processed for the purposes.

### Right to revocation of the declaration of consent under data protection law

You have the right to revoke your declaration of consent under data protection law at all times. The lawfulness of the processing carried out owing to the consent until the revocation will not be affected by the revocation of the consent.

This right is concluded from Art. 7 Para. 3 GDPR. This link _http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679 &rid=1_

will lead you directly to the text of the GDPR law.

### Right to lodge a complaint at a supervisory authority

Irrespective of any other legal remedy under administrative law or in court you are entitled to the right to lodge a complaint at a supervisory authority, in particular in the member state of your habitual residence, your place of workor the place of the alleged infringement if you consider are of the opinion that the processing of the personal data relating to you breaches the GDPR.

The supervisory authority, at which the complaint was lodged, will inform the complainant about the status and the results of the complaint including the possibility of a legal remedy in court according to Art. 78 GDPR.

### Cookie List

Please [click here for our updated list of currently used cookies](https://travelaudience.com/cookie-list/) for the travel audience website.
